<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on Nikita Vaniasin, Software Engineer</title>
    <link>https://vaniasin.com/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on Nikita Vaniasin, Software Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 09:10:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vaniasin.com/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making ClickHouse ch-go client more user-friendly</title>
      <link>https://vaniasin.com/chh-making-clickhouse-ch-go-user-friendly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 09:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaniasin.com/chh-making-clickhouse-ch-go-user-friendly/</guid>
      <description>ClickHouse is a fast open-source column-oriented database management system that allows generating analytical data reports using SQL queries.
We were using it for some time in our Golang application with the most popular clickhouse-go/v2 driver package which served nice and allowed writing queries in fast and clean way.
Recently I came across the benchmarks for different ClickHouse go drivers comparing the performance for simple select: https://github.com/ClickHouse/ch-bench#benchmarks. I was surprised at the difference between clickhouse-go/v2 and ch-go packages and decided to do a bit of research, especially since I wanted to optimize response times for some of our requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projectional editing</title>
      <link>https://vaniasin.com/code-morass-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 19:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vaniasin.com/code-morass-editor/</guid>
      <description>Всем привет.  Это пост для тех, кто каждый день пишет код. Как вы вероятно знаете, я таки аспирант. Аспиранты в аспирантуре делают полезные дела и придумывают всякие безумные штуки, чтобы защитить кандидатскую диссертацию (зачем они это делают — тема для отдельного поста). Короче. Обычно люди не охотно делают то, что никому не нужно. А я не знаю, нужен ли мой проект кому-то. Поэтому пишу этот пост в первую очередь, чтобы собрать фидбек.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
